lastminute.com 2008-05-13

# Terms and conditions

**Terms and Conditions**

This is the user agreement which governs your use of this website or, if relevant, one of our other distribution channels (such as Interactive TV ("IDTV"), mobile telephone commerce ("WAP") or interactive voice technology ("IVT") (the "Channels") and the purchase by you of the services and products we provide. Each Channel is owned and operated by a member of the lastminute.com limited group ("lastminute.com", "we", "us") however not all of the products or services we provide are supplied by us, therefore the contract for the product and/or service will be between you and that third party. 

**General Section - please note that this section relates generally to your use of any Channel and to all products purchased.**

  1. Please take time to read these terms and conditions it is important for both of us that you understand our contractual relationship relating to your use of the Channels. We will not allow you to purchase any products from any of the Channels unless you have confirmed that you have read these terms.
  2. Except for the sale of a very small number of products (such as, for some entertainment tickets) our Channels operate to an agency model. This means that we act as a disclosed agent for third party suppliers, such as a tour operator, hotel or a restaurant. What this means is that the contract for the product is between you and the supplier. In most cases this will mean that there are additional terms and conditions governing the contract as each supplier will have terms and conditions relating to that product. Please make sure that you have read these terms and conditions before completing your transaction with us. You can easily request them from our Customer Services by using one of the methods detailed at the end of these terms. Where we act as agent this will mean that we have no contractual liability to you in respect of that product. However, we may still be liable to you if we have been negligent, we have misrepresented important information or have been in breach of any other relevant law. On the other hand, for some products, we act as principal. This means that the contract for the product is between you and us. Don't worry we will let you know where we act as principal and where we act as agent.
  3. All products sold through lastminute.com's Channels are not an offer by lastminute.com to sell any product, but an invitation to you to make an offer to our suppliers. We are free to accept that offer on behalf of those suppliers or to reject it. In some cases, we may send you an email acknowledging receipt of your order. Once we have processed your order, we will send you an e-mail confirming the contract if you are purchasing from the website, from other Channels the confirmation may be different. For example when purchasing via WAP we will send you an SMS or via IVT our acceptance will be communicated when the product is delivered. The method of concluding a contract will be made clear on the relevant Channel. 
  4. Because the contract for the product is between you and the supplier any queries or concerns relating to the product should be addressed to them. You will see the name and address, plus contact details, for most suppliers at the bottom of the more info section for each product and for all suppliers in any confirmatory e-mail we send you. We will of course assist you with this if you wish - please contact Customer Services. 
  5. Where your contract is not with lastminute.com but with a third party supplier such as a tour operator or hotel, lastminute.com may pass your credit card (or details of any other payment method allowed) and any other essential booking details to that third party. The placing of an order for any goods and services by you will constitute consent to us passing on such details. 
  6. Please make sure that you have read and understood the more info sections on the Channels, it is your responsibility to make sure you have done so. 
  7. You undertake to us that the details you give to us while using the Channels are correct in particular that the credit or debit card you are using is your own and that there are sufficient funds to cover the cost of the product or service. 
  8. If there are any changes to the details supplied to us by you it is your responsibility to inform lastminute.com via our web form or by contacting our Customer Services as soon as possible. 
  9. We won't send you e-mails which you do not want but we can't guarantee that third parties to whom your details are sent won't do so. 
  10. Our Channels will not stop you from making impossible bookings such as two flights to the same place at the same time or a flight to one place and theatre tickets to another at the same time. If you make that kind of booking we won't give you a refund. 
  11. We will do our best to correct errors and omissions as quickly as practicable after being notified of them. However because of the sophisticated technology that is required in operating lastminute.com there may be times when obvious errors occur. For example, very occasionally, this may result in a price, product or service or other detail displayed or presented on a Channel being incorrect. In this case we reserve the right to cancel that contract, but this of course will be without any liability to you. 
  12. lastminute.com does not make any warranty that the website is free from infection by viruses or anything else that has contaminating or destructive properties. 
  13. Credit card companies charge us a fee when you pay with their cards and therefore a credit card fee is applied to some travel bookings made with Visa, MasterCard or American Express credit cards. Currently, credit card fees are charged on flights, flight and hotel packages and hotel bookings. 

**Specific Terms - Please note these terms only relate to the purchase of the specific products to which they relate. Please note if there is a conflict or ambiguity between these Special Terms and the General Terms the Special Terms shall prevail:**

Click below for Terms and Conditions relating to:   

  * A **Data Protection and Privacy**  

  * B **Flights.**   
1\. Regular Flights   
2\. Charter Flights  
3\. No Frills Airlines  

  * C  **Holidays and other travel related products ("Holiday Products")**  

  * D  **Hotels**  

  * E  **Eurostar**  

  * F **Airport Car Parking**  

  * G **Travel Insurance**  

  * H **Carbonwise**  

  * I **Gifts & Experiences ("Gifts")**  

  * J **Restaurants**  

  * K **Sports, Theatre, Music and Entertainment Tickets ("Tickets")**  

  * L **Gift Vouchers**  

  * M **Auction**  

  * N **Other Miscellaneous Section**   

|  |   
  
---|---  
   
|   
A. **Data Protection and Privacy Policy February 2004 for the lastminute.com site**

  1. Please find below our privacy policy for the lastminute.com site which shall be deemed to be incorporated into these terms and conditions. We are Last Minute Network Limited (trading as 'lastminute.com') and our registered address is 39 Victoria Street, London, SW1E 6JP. lastminute.com takes the privacy of its customers data very seriously. Please read the following policy to understand how we will treat your personal data after it has been collected by us through your use of one of our distribution channels. Those distribution channels will include our website, our WAP, PDA and digital TV services our Interactive Voice Recognition software and other channels as they evolve. If this policy changes then we will let you know via our homepage but we assure you that we only use your data as specified here and for our legitimate business reasons. 
  2. **When do we collect data?**

We can collect data on you from a variety of different sources these include. 

1\. When you purchase products or services from the site or via any of our other distribution channels.   
2\. When you become a subscriber;   
3\. When you speak to our customer services personnel;   
4\. Via explicit data capture measures, for example by entering competitions and completing surveys;   
5\. Via implicit data capture measures such as studying which pages you read the most and the use of cookies.   
In any of the above cases the data we collect could be personal data. 

  3. **What do we do with your personal information?**

When you buy anything via the site or give us any personal data as indicated above , we may need to collect information about you to process the transaction, fulfill your order and provide you with the services you expect then and in the future. This information may include, but is not limited to, details such as your name, your address, your phone number and your credit card details. 

  4. Unless we have your express consent we will only disclose personal data to third parties if this is required for the purpose of completing your transaction with us. This is of course subject to the proviso that we may disclose your data to certain permitted third parties, such as members of our own group, our own professional advisers who are bound by confidentiality codes, and when we are legally obliged to disclose your data. 
  5. By becoming a subscriber you consent to receive from us by e-mail our e-newsletter and details of other special offers which we may think may be of interest to you. 
  6. By subscribing to our 'lastminute.com onthemove' SMS services you consent to receive from us by SMS. MMS, EMS or voice-message our m-newsletter and details of other special offers which we may think may be of interest to you. 
  7. lastminute.com retains and uses your personal information to provide you with the best remote commerce (including electronic and mobile commerce) experience by providing you with a personalised service and to give you details of offers which we think will be of interest to you. We may also use the information to process any transactions you undertake with us and for internal administration and analysis. For quality assurance and training reasons we record most of the calls you make to us. 
  8. We do not sell, rent or trade your personal information to third parties for marketing purposes without your express consent. 
  9. For any of the above purposes we may send your information internationally including to countries outside the EEA. Some of these jurisdictions offer differing levels of protection of personal information, not all of which may be as high as the UK. 
  10. Beginning 1 January 2004, the personal information that you submit to us through the lastminute.com auction site will be collected, stored and processed at our third party service provider's data centre in the Canada. Canada has data protection laws that are as stringent than those in the UK. 
  11. By becoming a lastminute.com auction customer you consent to the collection, storage and processing of your personal information in Canada. 
  12. **Cookies**

Each web site owned and operated by the lastminute.com group uses cookies. A cookie is a small text file of which there are three types:  
Session cookies: These are used to maintain something called session state. If you consider your journey through the site to be a conversation with us and this cookie just reminds the site where we were in that conversation (for instance if at some point in the conversation you asked us to add a hotel to your basket, next time you click on the basket it is still there). These are required for the site to function but are not used in any way to identify you personally. 

**Permanent cookies:** These store a few numbers on your hard drive. You can view them by looking in the cookies directory of your browser installation if you are interested. They last for a long time and each time you come to our site you send us a copy of them. We use them to identify you between visits. For instance if you were looking at hotels in London last time you were on the site and we have a great hotel deal we may use this cookie to recognise you and show you our great deal. They are not required for the site to work but may enhance your experience. We do not store any personal data in these cookies, just a unique number that identifies you to us. 

**Third Party Cookies:** You may have noticed that we carry advertising from third parties on our site. Occasionally they may send you a cookie. We have no control over these. 

Although you cannot block "session" cookies as they are required for our site to function correctly you can configure your internet browser so that it can reject both "permanent" and "third party" cookies. How you do this will depend upon the internet browser you use (for example, Internet Explorer 5, Netscape 4 or Opera etc) and it is therefore impractical for us to detail here how you can reject those cookies. Please refer to the relevant internet browser manufacturer's website where you should be able to receive all the information you need."   
**  
**

  13. **Third Party Advertising**   
The ads appearing on this Web site are delivered to you, on our behalf, by our Web advertising partner. Information about your visit to this site, such as number of times you have viewed an ad (but not your name, address, or any other personal information), is used to serve ads.

To opt out of third party advertising, visit the **[doubleclick website](http://www.doubleclick.com/us/about_doubleclick/privacy/ad-cookie/default.asp)**.  
**  
**

  14. **Data**  
In the UK we operate and are registered in accordance with applicable data protection legislation.   
**  
**
  15. **Consent**  
By disclosing your personal information to us using this website or over the telephone, you consent to the collection, storage and processing of your personal information by lastminute.com in the manner set out in this Privacy Policy. Some information and e-mails sent to lastminute.com may be used as testimonials but no e-mail address or contact details will be displayed.   
**  
**
  16. **Opt-Out Policy**  
lastminute.com Newsletter subscribers have the option to opt-out of receiving further information from us. Click here to unsubscribe.   
**  
**
  17. **Change/Modify Details**  
To change your e-mail address details, send an e-mail with your correct details to: [**changeme@lastminute.com** ](mailto:%20changeme@lastminute.com%20)  
If you need to Modify or Change your personal details after you have made a purchase on the site please contact us as soon as possible. 
  18. **Contact**  
If you have any questions or concerns about the information we hold about you, you can also **contact us**.  

|  |   
  
---|---  
   
|   

|  |   
  
---|---  
   
|   
**B. Flights**

**(i) Regular Flights**

  1. When you purchase a flight from lastminute.com you are using a service provided by Globepost Limited, a company which is a member of the lastminute.com limited group. 
  2. Globepost Limited is registered in England and Wales with registered number 01700807\. Its registered address is 39 Victoria Street, London, SW1E 6JP. 
  3. Generally, the more flexible the ticket the more expensive it is likely to be and you need to take various points into consideration before deciding between the fares on offer. 
  4. To help you, below are Globepost Limited's general booking conditions. Please read them carefully. 
  5. **Contract  
**  
Any booking made or order placed by you, whether through the lastminute.com website or otherwise, shall be deemed an offer by you to purchase the relevant items subject to these booking conditions. Note that Globepost Limited are selling the tickets as agents for the airlines, which means the contract for the flight product will be between you and the airline.

**Please note that for each ticket there are additional terms which are specific to that fare. They may, for example, state that the ticket is non-cancellable or non - refundable, and have other information relating to itinerary and refunds. You must read the FLIGHT RULES for each ticket. You can find the relevant FLIGHT RULES on the lastminute.com website when you progress through the purchase path.  
**  
You are responsible for complying with any airline's terms in relation to check-in times, reconfirmation of flights or other matters. In relation to flight tickets, you are required to use all flight coupons in order of sequence. If this requirement is not met the airline may void the ticket.

A contract arises between you and the airline when we send you a confirmation e-mail on behalf of Globepost Limited confirming that they have accepted your booking. 

  6. **Fares  
**  
All fares are quoted exclusive of taxes, plus the tax amount and then a total. These are added together to form your final quotation. Fares are subject to change without prior notice and are only guaranteed when following confirmation of the contract.
  7. **Reservations  
**  
In the vast majority of cases Globepost becomes aware of the availability of flights tickets for sale because it connects to large databases operated by third parties, which contain that availability. These databases are commonly called General Distribution Systems (GDS) or Central Reservation Systems (CRS), and it is through these GDS/CRS that Globepost purchases the relevant ticket. 

Be aware that certain airlines do not maintain "real time" seat availability in the GDS/CRS. Whilst every effort is made to reflect the true situation, instances may occur when airlines cancel sales. Globepost Limited will advise you within 48 hours if this is the case and will do all they can to reinstate your booking. 

Further, there are a tiny number of airlines which participate in the GDS/CRS, but do not participate in the UK Ticketing plan. In the unlikely event that you purchase tickets from an airline that does not participate in the UK Ticketing Plan, Globepost will be unable to issue the relevant tickets, and will have to terminate the reservation. 

In either instance we will not be liable for any additional costs incurred in having to purchase new tickets at a higher fare. Payment for tickets will of course be refunded to you if the reservation is terminated by the airline or us.   

  8. **Tickets** If it is not possible to get your flight tickets to you (eg because your travel date is imminent) we may insist that you have an "e-ticket" generated. This means that you will have to pick up your ticket at your point of departure. Don't worry, Globepost will make sure you know exactly where to pick up your tickets. 
  9. **Flight Reconfirmation  
**  
All onward , outward and return flights must be reconfirmed with the relevant airlines at least 72 hours prior to the commencement of that leg of the journey. Globepost Limited accepts no responsibility for bookings cancelled due to non-compliance with rules set by that particular airline. Globepost also take no responsibility for any flight rescheduling en route.

In the event of a schedule change it is not always necessary to have your tickets revalidated, however in the event that this is necessary we will inform you in due course and issue new tickets for you to use on your journey. 

  10. **Passports/Visas/Health Requirements  
**  
Globepost and lastminute.com are very happy to inform you of current documentation requirements if you so require. It is incumbent upon you to ensure that you meet the passport, visa, health requirements of the countries you wish to visit and those that you transit (even if it is for a plane change). Many countries require that your passport should be valid for a period of (a minimum) six months from the date of arrival into that country. Neither Globepost nor lastminute.com accept any responsibility if you should be denied boarding or deported due to non-fulfilment of the above. 
  11. **Insurance  
**  
Globepost strongly urges you to carry appropriate travel insurance to cover you for cancellation, health, baggage etc. 
  12. **Airline regulations/conditions of carriage  
**  
Please note that in all transactions Globepost acts as agents of the airlines you have chosen to book on. Please read your ticket wallet for their conditions of carriage.
  13. **Cancellation / Amendments  
**  
If you need to change or cancel your travel plans, it is your responsibility to notify Globepost of such a request. Please note that some tickets are non-refundable and/or do not allow changes. 

Where changes/refunds are permitted by the airline, Globepost applies an administration fee of £45 per person for any modifications, changes or cancellations to fares. This will be regardless of the price or face value of the fare. Please note this fee is also charged in cases of airport tax refunds, when the fare is non-refundable. Any booking fees or credit card charges are non-refundable. 

In addition to the Globepost charges, most airlines also have a penalty or cancellation fee for any changes or cancellations to fares. Please ensure you read the FLIGHT RULES for the fare selected as cancellation and amendment charges imposed by the airline are notified in the flight rules. If you are holding a booking for which a ticket has been issued and you do not notify us of your desire to cancel, this will be treated as a "no show" and could result in you losing all that you paid. 

If you want to cancel your journey it is important that you notify us with utmost urgency. This enables us to cancel your reservation with the airline. To notify us of your request for an amendment or cancellation, please contact our Customer Services Team by telephone or via email, using our online [**contact form**](http://www.lastminute.com/site/help/homepage.html?templateName=ask), or through your [**purchase history**](https://www.lastminute.com/site/help/your-account/purchase-history.html). . 

Should you have received a paper ticket, we require the original ticket to be returned to us at the below address. 

Flight ticket returns  
lastminute.com  
Trinity Square  
23-59 Staines Road  
Hounslow  
TW3 3HE

On receipt of the ticket we will send you an acknowledgement that we have received it. If you have been issued an e-ticket, we do not require the ticket to be returned to us. 

Those tickets, which are refundable or cancelled by us, will be processed and refunded back to the card used at time of booking. Please be advised that the cancellation process could take up to 16 weeks from receipt of the ticket. Some tickets may need to be submitted to the airline for the cancellation and/or refund to be authorized. In this event your refund request may take longer, but we will advise you in our acknowledgement of the expected turnaround period. Please note that most airlines do not refund on part used tickets. Tickets, which are returned more than 1 year from date of issue, are classified as expired tickets and must be submitted to the airline for their authority to refund.

  14. **Lost Tickets** If you lose your tickets, it may be possible to re-issue them for a fee. The amount payable will depend on the circumstances of the loss and how close to the travel date you discover it. However, not all tickets can be re-issued; which is another good reason for ensuring you have sufficient insurance cover. Tickets will be dispatched to you in accordance with your instructions and we accept no responsibility for their delivery. Lost tickets which cannot be re-issued are refunded at the sole discretion of the airline, these refunds can take up to one year to be authorized. 
  15. **Liability** As Globepost acts as agent this will mean that it will have no contractual liability to you in respect of the flight product. However, it may still be liable to you if it has been negligent, it has misrepresented important information or has been in breach of any other relevant law. 
  16. **Unreasonable behaviour** If in the reasonable opinion of a person acting in authority you are not fit to travel, he or she may refuse to let you board the aircraft. Normally this happens if such person thinks you are likely to disturb or harm other passengers. In this case your contract with Globepost will end immediately and we will no longer be responsible for you. 
  17. **Globepost Limited Data Protection and Privacy Policy  
**  
**(a) What do we do with your personal information?  
**  
When you buy anything via the site or give us any personal data as indicated above , we may need to collect information about you to process the transaction, fulfill your order and provide you with the services you expect then and in the future. This information may include, but is not limited to, details such as your name, your address, your phone number and your credit card details. 

Unless we have your express consent we will only disclose personal data to third parties if this is required for the purpose of completing your transaction with us. This is of course subject to the proviso that we may disclose your data to certain permitted third parties, such as members of our own group, our own professional advisers who are bound by confidentiality codes, and when we are legally obliged to disclose your data. 

By becoming a subscriber you consent to receive from us by e-mail our e-newsletter and details of other special offers which we may think may be of interest to you. 

By subscribing to our 'lastminute.com onthemove' SMS services you consent to receive from us by SMS. MMS, EMS or voice-message our m-newsletter and details of other special offers which we may think may be of interest to you. 

Globepost retains and uses your personal information to provide you with the best remote commerce (including electronic and mobile commerce) experience by providing you with a personalised service and to give you details of offers which we think will be of interest to you. We may also use the information to process any transactions you undertake with us and for internal administration and analysis. For quality assurance and training reasons we record most of the calls you make to us. 

We do not sell, rent or trade your personal information to third parties for marketing purposes without your express consent. 

For any of the above purposes we may send your information internationally including to countries outside the EEA. Some of these jurisdictions offer differing levels of protection of personal information, not all of which may be as high as the UK. 

**(b) Cookies  
**  
Each web site owned and operated by the lastminute.com group, including Globepost, uses cookies. A cookie is a small text file of which there are three types:

Session cookies: These are used to maintain something called session state. If you consider your journey through the site to be a conversation with us and this cookie just reminds the site where we were in that conversation (for instance if at some point in the conversation you asked us to add a hotel to your basket, next time you click on the basket it is st
